Keiron Goodwin

Software Engineer

Sheffield, S13

Mobile: +44 07471 947226

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/keiron-lee-goodwin-aab541a

Email: keirong@gmail.com

Personal Profile

A software engineer with over 20 years' experience in software development. Over the years I've worked using Linux and Windows environments in front end and back-end code for a well-known internet provider Plusnet. Also worked on ERP systems and back-end software used to process information received from mobile devices engineers use out in the field.

The past 17 years I've been working on developing and maintaining an ERP system mainly in the financial area but also in Stock, Purchasing and Sales on occasion. Prior to this I worked in a Windows and Linux environment working on the back end financial code and general front-end code for the Plusnet portal. Eager to use my skills and experience in web development to support the business and aid it in continuing to grow.

Skills

- ➤ Visual Basic 6/VB.Net
- Pick Data basic/Unidata
- Database
- Problem Solving
- JavaScript
- ▶ PHP
- MySQL
- SQL Server
- ➤ HTML 5
- ➤ CSS
- Bootstrap 5
- Net Framework 4
- ➤ WPF
- MVC
- Silverlight
- jQuery
- Customer support
- Time management
- > Team Leading

Work Experience

Sanderson, Software Developer, July 2003 - October 2020

Developed forms within VB6 in various areas of ERP system, those being Purchasing, Sales, HR, Wages, Financial, Stock control. Shortly before leaving I stayed on for a few months in the role of customer support specialist.

- Created an add on for Microsoft Outlook in VB.Net to process incoming emails from customers and automate ordering amongst other things.
- Worked on forms for a new version of the ERP software in C# and Typescript, also using HTML5, CSS, WPF, MVC, Silverlight, .NET Framework 4 amongst other technology.
- Dealt with customers when support was required for bugs and modifications.

PlusNet, Software Developer, January 2001 – September 2002

Worked within a LAMP stack developing the financial back-end code for customer billing via BACS etc. Worked on front end web pages on the main PlusNet website adding amongst other things site usage tracking software. Also gained experience acting as team leader when the main team leader was absent.

TBS, Software Developer, January 2000 – January 2001

I rewrote data processing end of Taskmaster software using VB6 to include use of custom DLLs written for or by customers. Also wrote cursors for use in SQL Server

Education & Qualifications

2005 – 2011 Sheffield University HNC Archaeology (Part of Human and Natural Environments degree)

1997 – 1999 Sheffield Hallam University HND Computer Science

Projects

Local Tourism Website

Deployed: Local Tourism Site

GitHub: Code for Local Tourism Site

Project done for bootcamp at the Developer Academy, the site shows examples of photography I've done in three local tourist areas in and around Sheffield with a bit of information about each area and a map to show viewers of the site where to go. Each photograph has a little information about it as well. Needs polishing up a bit but quite happy about the layout and appearance of the site.

Adventure Game

Deployed: Adventure Game site

GitHub: Code for Adventure Game site

This project again was done for part of the ongoing bootcamp course with the Developer Academy, we were asked to create a text adventure game using JavaScript, I however decided to take this one step further and create a graphical adventure game with text descriptions as well (just to cover myself), I decided to try and come up with a modern day version of a game I used to play in the mid 80's on a Mattel Aquarius, it still needs to be finished but it's playable in a very limited form at the minute. If you would like a play the W, A, S, D keys control movement in north, south, east, west style directions, Q and E turn left and right respectively, R is used to loot defeated enemies, SPACE BAR attacks creatures you come across and H uses a health potion if you have one in your inventory.

Quiz Project site

Deployed: Quiz Project site

GitHub: Code for Quiz Project site

This project is another one done as part of the bootcamp course at the Developer Academy, we were asked to create a quiz with multiple pages and options per question with a page that showed the results, it was meant to run as one page despite having multiple question pages. I decided to have a go at creating a quiz similar the the ones you find on social media sites that ask multiple questions and result in showing you which character you might be out of a film/tv/comic series. I decided to go with the X-Men. Quite happy with how it turned out although as with all the projects I do think that I should go back and polish them up a bit as I learn more.

Caesar Cypher site

Deployed: <u>Caesar Cypher site</u>

Code: Code for Caesar Cypher site

_Final project for now is another for the bootcamp course at the Developer Academy, the remit for this one was to create a site that involved using the Caesar Cypher to encode plain text and allow you to decrypt it afterwards, I extended this by allowing the user to use multiple key codes to encrypt the text. Quite happy with both the layout and how this turned out, code wise it was rather easy to complete but I think the simple design looks good too.

Personal Interests

Always hungry to learn and over the years I've been to college and university whilst working to further my knowledge, courses from learning new languages through to Photography and Archaeology of which the latter two have become big interests for me which I try to get involved in whenever possible (usually during warmer weather!). The past 5 years I have also had the opportunity to get involved in acting starting out with being a zombie extra in a few films through to playing a character in a locally produced comedy series called Up North.

Also linking in with the acting, I have also had the opportunity to mix my interest in photography and films using a drone to help create the opening credits to the Up North series as well as this I've also created a short landscape film around Rivelin Valley, it was accepted into three festivals and I won several awards in one of these including best short film.

I do believe archaeology has helped me to pay more attention to details I would perhaps have overlooked before and the photography/film making side is helping to open up a more creative side, both of which I think will add value to me as a prospective employee and on top of this I am always eager to learn more and develop my skills.